Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And we're bringing you another great elementary lesson today, one that takes place at the
今天我们为大家带来另一节很棒的基础课程，这节课发生在
office.
办公室。
Yes.
是的。
Today, we're going to teach you some great phrases so that you can ask people to help
今天，我们将教你们一些很棒的短语，这样你们就可以请别人帮忙
you.
了。
Right.
没错。
And I think this dialogue is with a new person at the office.
我觉得这段对话是关于办公室里的一个新人的。
So when you're new, you always need to ask people for favors.
所以当你刚来的时候，你总是需要请别人帮忙。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, we're going to be asking for a favor.
那么，我们将会请求帮忙。
So, Marco, what exactly is a favor?
那么，Marco，到底什么是帮忙？
Something that a person does for you.
就是别人为你做的事情。
Like a small, helpful thing.
比如一件小的、有帮助的事情。
Yeah, a small, helpful thing.
是的，一件小的、有帮助的事情。
So, you know, like, can you pass me that pencil?
所以，你知道，比如，你能把那支铅笔递给我吗？
Maybe that's even a favor.
也许那甚至算个忙。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or maybe, can you pick me up on your way to work?
或者，你能在上班路上顺道接我吗？
Yeah, that's a favor.
对，那算个忙。
Or even lending money to your friend.
甚至借钱给朋友也算。
That's a favor.
那算个忙。
Yeah.
嗯。
So that's what we're going to be talking about, favors and how to ask for one.
所以这就是我们要讨论的——帮忙以及如何请求帮忙。
Because you always have to do this at work.
因为你在工作中总是要这么做。
At work, with your friends, with your family.
工作中，和朋友，和家人。
So let's listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and explain all the vocabulary.
那么我们先听对话，然后回来解释所有词汇。
Um, sorry to bother you.
嗯，不好意思打扰一下。
My name is Rachel.
我叫瑞秋。
I'm new here.
我是新来的。
Can I ask you for a favor?
能请你帮个忙吗？
Hi, Rachel.
嗨，瑞秋。
Welcome on board.
欢迎加入。
I'm afraid I can't help you right now.
恐怕我现在帮不了你。
I'm getting ready for a very important meeting.
我正在准备一个非常重要的会议。
Excuse me, but can I bother you for a second?
打扰一下，能耽误你一会儿吗？
You know what?
你知道吗？
I'd love to help you, but I'm about to meet an important client.
我很想帮你，但我正要见一个重要客户。
Do you want to ask Sean instead?
你要不要去找肖恩？
He sits right over there.
他就坐在那边。
Sorry to interrupt you, Sean.
抱歉打扰你，肖恩。
Could you do me a quick favor?
你能帮我个小忙吗？
Actually, I'm working on a document that's due in a couple of minutes.
其实，我正在赶一份几分钟后就要交的文件。
I really can't talk right now.
我现在真的没法说话。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Geez.
天哪。
I just want to know where the bathroom is.
我只想知道洗手间在哪里。
What's wrong with you people?
你们这些人怎么回事？
So a pretty busy office.
所以是个相当忙碌的办公室。
Pretty unhelpful colleagues.
相当不帮忙的同事。
I know.
我知道。
Everyone's so busy they didn't help this poor girl.
每个人都太忙了，都没帮这个可怜的女孩。
Yeah, I hope she found the bathroom.
是啊，希望她找到了洗手间。
Now let's take a look at the language from the dialogue.
现在让我们看看对话中的语言。
So let's start with language takeaway.
我们先从语言要点开始。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
There's some great language in this dialogue, wasn't there?
这段对话里有些很棒的语言点，对吧？
Yeah, a lot of interesting phrases and words.
是啊，很多有趣的短语和词汇。
The first one that I saw that was really interesting is on board.
我注意到的第一个非常有趣的是“on board”。
On board.
On board。
Welcome on board.
欢迎加入。
Well, we've got some examples of how this phrase is used.
我们有一些这个短语的使用例子。
So let's listen to them to help us understand the meaning.
让我们听一下，以帮助理解它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
Welcome on board, Sarah.
欢迎加入，莎拉。
If you have any questions, please feel free to ask me.
如果你有任何问题，请随时问我。
Example two.
例子二。
We need to get our new office assistant on board as soon as possible.
我们需要尽快让新的办公室助理入职。
Example three.
例子三。
We decided to bring Melissa on board to join the marketing team.
我们决定让梅丽莎加入营销团队。
So basically it means...
所以基本上它的意思是……
Welcome to the company.
欢迎加入公司。
Or...
或者……
The team.
团队。
Yeah.
是的。
Welcome on board.
欢迎加入。
So on board is the same as to the company.
所以“on board”和“加入公司”是一个意思。
I guess also when you get on a ship, they'll tell you welcome on board.
我想当你上船时，他们也会对你说“欢迎登船”。
Yes, that's where it comes from.
是的，这个词就是这么来的。
Or an airplane.
或者上飞机。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
Welcome on board.
欢迎登机。
Okay, let's take a look at our next word.
好的，我们来看下一个词。
About to.
即将。
I'm about to.
我正要去做。
So this is a great phrase to explain that you're about to do something.
所以这是一个很好的短语，用来解释你即将做某事。
I'm going to do this thing really soon.
我很快就要做这件事了。
Okay, so for example, you can say, I'm about to go out for lunch.
好的，比如你可以说，我正要出去吃午饭。
Or I could say, hey Marco, let's go record a show.
或者我可以说，嘿，Marco，我们去录节目吧。
I'm about to go into a meeting.
我正要开会。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
About to.
正要。
Going to do something really soon.
很快就要做某事了。
Okay.
好的。
The next word we have is instead.
我们下一个词是 instead。
Instead.
Instead。
It means in the place of.
它的意思是“代替”。
In the place of.
代替。
Yep.
是的。
So for example, if we're at dinner, I could say, I'll have the chicken instead of the
比如，我们在吃晚餐时，我可以说，我要鸡肉而不是
fish.
鱼。
Right?
对吧？
Or I can say, I wanted to buy a red sweater, but they didn't have one, so I bought a blue
或者我可以说，我想买一件红毛衣，但他们没有，所以我买了一件蓝色的
one instead.
来代替。
Instead.
代替。
Okay.
好的。
So in the place of.
所以是“代替”的意思。
Yep.
是的。
And our last word for language takeaway, interrupt.
我们语言要点的最后一个词是“打断”。
Interrupt.
打断。
So when somebody interrupts you, they come in and.
所以当有人打断你时，他们进来并。
They talk to you while you're doing something or maybe while you're speaking.
他们在你做某事或说话时跟你说话。
Or maybe you're busy and people come and.
或者你可能很忙，人们过来并。
Bother you.
打扰你。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So interrupt.
所以打断一下。
Interrupt.
打断一下。
Okay, some great words here in our dialogue and now we can listen to it again.
好的，我们的对话中有一些很棒的词汇，现在我们可以再听一遍。
This time it's going to be a little bit slower.
这次会稍微慢一点。
And you'll be able to understand the language a little bit better.
这样你就能更好地理解这些语言了。
Sorry to bother you.
抱歉打扰你。
My name is Rachel.
我叫瑞秋。
I'm new here.
我是新来的。
Can I ask you for a favor?
能请你帮个忙吗？
Hi Rachel.
嗨，瑞秋。
Welcome on board.
欢迎登机。
I'm afraid I can't help you right now.
恐怕我现在帮不了你。
I'm getting ready for a very important meeting.
我正在准备一个非常重要的会议。
Excuse me, but can I bother you for a second?
打扰一下，能耽误你一会儿吗？
You know what?
你知道吗？
I'd love to help you, but I'm about to meet an important client.
我很想帮你，但我正要见一位重要客户。
Do you want to try Sean instead?
你要不要找肖恩试试？
He sits right over there.
他就坐在那边。
Sorry to interrupt you, Sean.
抱歉打扰你，肖恩。
Could you do me a quick favor?
能帮我个小忙吗？
Actually I'm working on a document that is due in a couple of minutes.
其实我正在赶一份几分钟后就要交的文件。
I really can't talk to you right now.
我现在真的没法跟你说话。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Jeez.
天哪。
I just want to know where the bathroom is.
我只想知道洗手间在哪儿。
What's wrong with you people?
你们这些人怎么回事？
Okay, so there are some great ways that you can ask someone for a favor, right?
好，有一些很棒的方法可以请别人帮忙，对吧？
Yeah, we want to show you some really useful phrases for asking for help.
是的，我们想给你展示一些非常实用的求助短语。
So let's start with putting it together.
那我们从“整合”开始吧。
Putting it together.
整合。
Let's listen to some different ways of how you can ask someone for a favor.
让我们听听一些不同的请求别人帮忙的方式。
Example one.
示例一。
May I get you to do me a favor?
能请你帮我一个忙吗？
Can you carry this package in your suitcase for me?
你能帮我把这个包裹放在你的行李箱里吗？
Example two.
示例二。
Can I ask you a favor?
我能请你帮个忙吗？
Can you just finish this report for me?
你能帮我把这份报告完成吗？
Example three.
示例三。
Will you do me a favor and pass me that file?
能帮我一个忙，把那个文件递给我吗？
Okay, so those were great examples of asking for a favor.
好了，这些都是请求帮忙的很好的例子。
In our dialogue we heard, can I ask you a favor?
在我们的对话中，我们听到了“能请你帮个忙吗？”
But we could also say, can I get you to do me a favor?
但我们也可以说“能请你帮我个忙吗？”
Right.
对。
Can I get you to do me a favor?
能请你帮我个忙吗？
Also, I could say, will you do me a favor?
另外，我可以说“你愿意帮我个忙吗？”
Will you do me a favor?
你愿意帮我个忙吗？
Right.
对。
So those are different ways of asking for a favor.
所以这些都是请求帮忙的不同方式。
Let's say you want to ask someone for a favor, right?
假设你想请某人帮忙，对吧？
But they're busy.
但他们很忙。
So you'll need some phrases to help you do this.
所以你需要一些短语来帮助你做到这一点。
Exactly.
没错。
You need some phrases to interrupt somebody, right?
你需要一些打断别人的短语，对吧？
So let's listen to some examples of what phrases you can use to begin to talk to someone.
那么让我们听一些例子，看看可以用哪些短语开始和别人交谈。
Yeah, to interrupt them.
是的，打断他们。
Okay.
好的。
I hate to bother you, but...
我不想打扰你，但是……
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
抱歉打扰你，但是……
I don't mean to bother you, but...
我不想打扰你，但是……
Okay, so those are really nice and polite ways of beginning to talk to someone.
好的，这些是非常友好和礼貌的开始交谈的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
They're really useful at the office.
它们在办公室里非常有用。
So maybe you want to talk to your boss, you knock on his door, kind of open it a little
所以也许你想和老板谈话，你敲他的门，稍微打开一点
bit and say, I'm sorry to bother you, but I was wondering if you have time for a meeting
然后说：“抱歉打扰您，我想知道您今天是否有时间开个会？”
today?
今天？
Or you could say, I hate to bother you, but do you have time for a meeting today?
或者你可以说：“我不想打扰您，但您今天有时间开个会吗？”
Exactly.
没错。
So those are great ways of starting up a conversation and maybe setting it up to ask for a favor,
所以这些都是开启对话的好方法，也许还能为请求帮助做铺垫，
right?
对吧？
So we can combine them.
所以我们可以把它们结合起来。
I could say, I hate to bother you, but can you do me a favor?
我可以说，我不想打扰你，但你能帮我个忙吗？
Perfect.
完美。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah, really useful.
是的，非常有用。
So then you can ask someone for a favor.
这样你就可以请别人帮忙了。
Yep.
嗯。
Okay, great stuff.
好的，很棒的内容。
So I guess we can listen to our dialogue again.
所以我想我们可以再听一遍我们的对话。
Yeah, let's listen to our dialogue for the third time and this time I'm sure you'll understand
是的，让我们第三次听我们的对话，这次我确定你会理解得
it a lot better.
更好。
I'm sorry to bother you.
抱歉打扰你。
My name is Rachel.
我叫瑞秋。
I'm new here.
我是新来的。
Can I ask you for a favor?
能请你帮个忙吗？
Hi, Rachel.
嗨，瑞秋。
Welcome on board.
欢迎登机。
I'm afraid I can't help you right now.
恐怕我现在帮不了你。
I'm getting ready for a very important meeting.
我正在为一个非常重要的会议做准备。
Excuse me, but can I bother you for a second?
打扰一下，能耽误你一会儿吗？
You know what?
你知道吗？
I'd love to help you, but I'm about to meet an important client.
我很想帮你，但我马上要见一个重要客户。
Do you want to ask Sean instead?
你要不要去找肖恩？
He sits right over there.
他就坐在那边。
Sorry to interrupt you, Sean.
抱歉打扰你，肖恩。
Could you do me a quick favor?
能帮我个小忙吗？
Actually, I'm working on a document that's due in a couple of minutes.
其实我正在赶一份文件，几分钟后就要交了。
I really can't talk right now.
我现在真的没法说话。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Geez, I just want to know where the bathroom is.
天哪，我只想知道洗手间在哪儿。
What's wrong with you people?
你们这些人怎么回事？
Alright so now you have all the vocabulary necessary the next time you need to ask someone
好了，现在你已经掌握了下次需要请人帮忙时
for a favor.
所需的全部词汇。
Yes.
是的。
You can do that in your office, with your friends, with your family, anyone.
你可以在办公室、和朋友、家人，对任何人都可以这样做。
Well everyone, we are out of time for today, but remember to visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
好了各位，今天的时间到了，但记得访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Exactly at our website you'll find the script of the dialogue and also you'll find intermediate
在我们的网站上，你会找到对话的文本，还有中级
lessons, upper intermediate and even advanced.
课程、中高级甚至高级课程。
Yeah exactly.
没错。
Our website is a great resource for learning.
我们的网站是学习的好资源。
Marco and I are always there to answer your questions and we also have lots of helpful
Marco 和我随时都在那里回答你们的问题，我们还有很多乐于助人的
users who answer your questions.
用户来回答你们的问题。
Exactly so don't miss out.
没错，所以别错过了。
Come to our website at EnglishPod.com and we'll see you there.
来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里等你。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Good Sarmalee until next time.
再见 Sarmalee，下次见。